Hello.
My name is Grady Johnson and I'm a professional painter.
Now we're going to talk a little bit about pressure washing.
The reason we're talking about pressure washing is it's crucial to pressure wash the exterior of your house before you do any painting.
It's not that you can't paint without pressure washing.
It's just that the paint's not going to stick as well as it will adhere to a cleaner surface.
Now, with pressure washers there's a couple of kinds you can get.
You can get the gas powered ones which are the best and the strongest.
Or you can get something like I'm using today, an electric pressure washer.
Now on this job, it's not really peeling bad.
It doesn't get a lot of sunlight, so it's not too bad.
If you've got a lot of heavy chalking or a lot of peeling, then you want a really, really strong, gas powered pressure washer.
But on something lite like this, I just used my standard electric pressure washer.
This is only about twelve hundred psi.
There's not a lot to it.
So it doesn't have as much strength as a big one.
But it's not going to need as much because mostly we're just going to get the dirt off.
We're going to take out these old cobwebs that are up in the eaves, that kind of thing.
This is why today we're going to go ahead and use this standard old electric pressure washer.
Now, these are really easy to turn on.
It's just a button in the back, back here.
Push the button and you're going to hear it whir up.
That means the pressure is good.
Then, you just kind of want to test it and pull the trigger.
Now you can see that's already set to about fifteen degrees.
That's going to be about what I normally work with.
That's why it's kind of sucky.
Now, that's enough to clean the I.N.
It still has pretty good pressure.
This pressure washer's only about twelve hundred psi.
That's pounds per square inch.
Now, when we're working, we're hoping we're not going to find many rough areas.
That's why we're using an electric.
Because mostly we're just washing.
But if we've found a rough area we want to go ahead and go to this tip, turn it all the way to the left side and you're going to get that needle nose.
That has the maximum pressure on the pressure washer.
That'll dig out any area that you have even if you have a stubborn cobweb that's up in a corner.
But normally, you're going to keep that at about fifteen.
Now that's just a matter of turning the wand tip.
That's about right.
Now, you're going to go ahead and get that up into the eaves and we want to get the back side as well.
Then, you want to go ahead and get the reverse side too.
You see, this is a pretty good paint job.
It's holding on pretty good.
Now, I'm going to bring my facing on down.
I'll work my way down the eaves that way.
Now, once I've got to a point that I like, I want to go ahead and get the rest of this section here while I'm here instead of making a lot of moves.
So, I'm going to need to get a little higher to get these jalous eaves.
So I kind of keep a ladder handy.
I'm going to pull that in now.
Pull that into place and jump up a couple of rungs.
Now once I'm up here, I can shoot down on it.
That way it'll work like rainwater.
This is where you really wash down all that grime.
It's a nice opportunity to get these sills too.
Now, all that's left is this bottom part on the wall.
We'll bring that on up and keep continuing on down.
This is how you pressure wash the exterior surface of a house to prepare it for painting.